[
    {
        "question": "In 1806, Indian soldiers at _________ revolted.",
        "options": [
            "Barrackpore",
            "Meerut",
            "Vellore",
            "Delhi"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The British adopted the policy of polluting the minds of Indians by following the _________.",
        "options": [
            "Strict rules",
            "Administration",
            "Divide and Rule policy",
            "War of Independence"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The Indian soldiers revolted in cantonments from _________ to Rajputana.",
        "options": [
            "Delhi",
            "Bihar",
            "Peth",
            "Kolhapur"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Chimasaheb : _________ :: Bhagoji Naik : Ahmednagar",
        "options": [
            "Kolhapur",
            "Pune",
            "Nagpur",
            "Peth"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "In the army of the _________, there were many Indian Sepoys.",
        "options": [
            "East India Company",
            "British",
            "Indian",
            "Barrackpore"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The British introduced a new _________ system to increase their income.",
        "options": [
            "Tax system",
            "Revenue",
            "Stable",
            "Tool tax"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "_________ was kept exclusively in the hands of the British.",
        "options": [
            "Artillery",
            "Cavalry",
            "Army",
            "Wealth"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Kajarsingh : Bhills :: Shankarshah : _________.",
        "options": [
            "Khandesh",
            "Satpura"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "British won the _________ war with Russia.",
        "options": [
            "Moscow",
            "London",
            "Ohio",
            "Crimean"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "The _________ of British soldiers was increased in the army.",
        "options": [
            "Number",
            "Proportion",
            "Percentage",
            "Graph"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Indian soldiers were brave but did not use _________.",
        "options": [
            "Intelligence",
            "Tactics",
            "Arms",
            "Artillery"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "_________ action was taken on those Sepoys who refused to use the smeared cartridges and were given severe punishment.",
        "options": [
            "Martial",
            "Army",
            "Disciplinary",
            "Hunter"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "An armed rebellion of Paikas against the British took place in _________.",
        "options": [
            "1817",
            "1820",
            "1818",
            "1819"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Taxes were _________ extracted from the farmers.",
        "options": [
            "Introduced",
            "Levy",
            "Forcibly",
            "Collapsed"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Since _________ was in the hands of the British their movements were swift.",
        "options": [
            "Transport and communication",
            "Disciplined army",
            "Strength",
            "Arms"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The _________ fought against Abdali at Panipat.",
        "options": [
            "Mughals",
            "Marathas",
            "British"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "_________ from Nasik district also participated in the struggle.",
        "options": [
            "Peth",
            "Kajarsingh",
            "Surgana",
            "Bhills"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The British accepted the policy of _________ in social and religious aspects of Indians.",
        "options": [
            "Interference",
            "Non-interference"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Queen _________ of England issued a Declaration addressing the people of India.",
        "options": [
            "Ruby",
            "Victoria"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "In the freedom struggle of 1857 the descendant of the Mughals _________ was incapable of fighting against the British.",
        "options": [
            "Bahadur Shah",
            "Rani Jhansi",
            "Nadirshah",
            "Abdali"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "In the _________ Hindu, Muslims stood up with a great force.",
        "options": [
            "Revolt",
            "Struggle",
            "Rebellion",
            "Discontent"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "There was no commonly accepted _________ to fight against the British.",
        "options": [
            "King",
            "Mughal",
            "Leader",
            "Nawab"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "In the army of East India company there were many _________ sepoys.",
        "options": [
            "British",
            "Indian",
            "Foreign"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    }
]
